A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia 1915-1919
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia 1915-1919
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.472 IV
This collection consists of ca. 2,000 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.)
Scope and Content Information
Correspondence and related papers (ca. 2,000 items) of President Edwin Anderson Alderman originally kept in the President's office and maintained in a separate file labelled "Personal."
Contents List
- Office Administrative Files 1915-1919
  - AMiscellaneous, reference to American Historical Society 1915-1919 (Box 1)
  - Alabama Survey, reference to Higher Education 1919 (Box 1)
  - BMiscellaneous, reference to Establishment of International Committee 1915-1919 (Box 1)
  - CMiscellaneous 1915-1919 (Box 1)
  - DMiscellaneous, reference to State Lime Grinding Plant Project 1915-1919 (Box 1)
  - E-F Miscellaneous, reference to Foreign Relations with Russia 1915-1919 (Box 1)
  - Financial Matters and Bill Lists 1915-1919 (Box 1)
  - GMiscellaneous, reference to Institute for Government Research 1915-1919 (Box 1)
  - General Election Board (1 of 4), reference to Report on Schools of Education 1915-1917 (Box 1)
  - General Election Board (2-3 of 4) 1915-1917 (Box 1)
  - General Election Board (4 of 4) 1918-1919 (Box 2)
  - Governor's Budget 1918-1919 (Box 2)
  - H-I Miscellaneous, reference to Children of America 1915-1919 (Box 2)
  - Hampton Institute--"Negro and Americanism" 1915-1919 (Box 2)
  - Invitations to Speak 1915-1919, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - J-L Miscellaneous 1915-1919 (Box 2)
  - Library of Southern Literature, reference to List of Sales 1915-1919 (Box 2)
  - MMiscellaneous 1915-1919 (Box 2)
  - Mc Miscellaneous 1915-1919 (Box 2)
  - N-O Miscellaneous, reference to National Institute of Social Sciences 1915-1919 (Box 3)
  - Naval Academy 1917-1919, 4 folders (Board of Visitors Reports in folder 1) (Box 3)
  - Pa-Pe Miscellaneous, reference to League to Enforce Peace 1915-1919 (Box 4)
  - Pi-Ro Miscellaneous 1915-1918 (Box 4)
  - Payne Will Material 1915-1919 (Box 4)
  - SMiscellaneous 1915-1919 (Box 4)
  - Southern Railway, director of 1915-1919 (Box 4)
  - T-V Miscellaneous refererence to Eloquent Tribute to Virginia; Twilight Club 1915-1919 (Box 4)
  - WMiscellaneous 1915-1919